ZARA SARI

zarasari1@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/zarasari | https://github.com/zarasari/

PROFILE

Analyst Statistician with a decade of experience in delivering results and providing efficient solutions. In my previous roles I have conducted statistical modelling and provided data insight using Python, SQL and SPSS within the insurance and medical research industry. I contribute to the team by utilising problem solving skills whilst strengthening my skillset.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Python: Pandas, StatsModel, Seaborn, MatplotLib, Sklearn
- Data techniques: visualisation, regression, machine learning, hypothesis testing
- SQL, Git, Tableau, IBM SPSS Text Analytics, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Word

EMPLOYMENT

Volunteer Data Analyst

July 2022 - Ongoing

Voluntary data work with DataKind UK and ad hoc data analysis with psi

Statistician - Reporting/ Data Analyst

May 2021 - July 2022

UKHSA - UK Health Security Agency

- Weekly publication of COVID-19 statistics for NHS test and trace (England)
- Automating data tables in R and Python, querying data from large database via SQL and version control using Git
- Navigating regulatory constraints in publishing within policy driven environment
- Publication ended due to government 'living with Covid' policy

Community Leader, Data Ambassador and VolunteerData Kind Charity (Ad-hoc role) January 2018 - Ongoing

• Led a team of volunteers to provide the non-profit organisation with answers and actionable insights, currently supporting the leadership team

Freelance Statistician

January 2021 - May 2021

Freshminds

- Contract role for a digital education and course provider company
- Updating products pricing utilising statistical techniques to support sales department

Analyst Statistician

September 2020 - December 2020

OBH (Outcomes Based Healthcare)

- Extracted and analysed secondary patient data using Electronic Health record
- Dealt with missing values and produced visual representation of NHSE NHS Digital
- Modelling and forecasting tools to predict mortality risk of COVID-19: Python, SQL
- Produced Kaplan-Meier plots and utilised Cox proportional hazards model

Senior Data Analyst

Domestic and General

August 2019 - February 2020

- Converted static excel sheets to visual powerBI reports to spot the latest trends
- Applied Statistical technique to answer business questions
- Managed work load of 2 team members

Analyst Statistician

March 2014 - April 2019

Thatcham Research

- Delivered a large project which helped prove cars with Autonomous Emergency Braking are safer by modelling frequency and severity loss experience of motor insurance claims
- Study results published for ESV (Enhanced Safety of Vehicles) conference
- Analysed, standardised and manipulated large databases, providing insight that solves real world problems and influences decisions: SPSS, R and SQL query
- Presented data insights in PowerPoint slides for non-technical audience
- Provided training and support for junior colleagues on the adoption of processes
- Automated monthly data tables QlickSense and Power BI

Freelance Statistician/ Data Analyst

November 2013 - March 2014

IAS (International Advisory Services)

Statistical analysis for Likert scale (categorical) survey data

Personal Tutor

January 2008 - November 2013

• One on one Mathematics and Statistics tutorials for GCSE, A-Level and University

EDUCATION

Team Leadership Certificate

2018

Newbury College, Distance Learning Course

M.B.A. International

2012 - 2013

Anglia Ruskin University, London campus

M.Sc. Statistics with Medical Applications

2010 - 2011

University of Sheffield

Dissertation: Risk Modelling for lung cancer data using England hospital data

B.Sc. (Hons) Actuarial Science University of Kent 2003 - 2006